Register of the Štefan Osuský Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1916-1971. (Box 32-68)
  - "The Soviet Encirclement of the Capitalist Countries," Free Europe Summer Session, Strasburg - Robertsau, 1961 August 5-27. (Folder 67: 21)
  - "Report on Germany," 1961 October 8. (Folder 67: 22)
  - Speech on the Anti-Communist Freedom Day, 1962 January 23. (Folder 67: 23)
    Notes, typescript, and printed copy
  - "Mes souvenirs sur Aristide Briand," Rencontres, Paris, 1962 January-March. (Folder 67: 24)
  - Review of Benjamin Cohen's address "The Great Powers and the United Nations," 1962 May 8. (Folder 67: 25)
  - "Where Great Britain Was and Whither She Was Tending," Washington, D.C., 1962 May 9. (Folder 67: 26)
  - "The Charter of the United Nations and a New World Order," 1962 July 15. (Folder 67: 27)
  - "Where America Is and Whither She Is Tending," Washington D.C., 1962 August 1. (Folder 67: 28)
  - "Communist Czechoslovakia and Khrushchev's World Revolution," lecture, Marquette University, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 1963 March 13. (Folder 67: 29)
  - "Postoj Moskvy k spoločnému trhu," speech, Sdruženie čsl. exulantů, Chicago, 1963 March 16. (Folder 67: 30)
    Typescript (in Slovak and English)
  - "Osuský Notes on Munich," 1963 December 13. (Box-folder 68: 1)
    Notes, holographs and typescript
  - "Final East-West Issue," radio speech, Reviewing Stand program of Voice of Freedom - Radio Free Europe, 1964 February 2. (Folder 68: 2)
  - "Na lži se budoucnost národa budovat nedá," 1967 February 27. (Folder 68: 3)
    Typescript (in Czech). Includes two typescripts under the titles "Mnichovská tragédie" and "Kalvárie Československa"
  - "Aké bolo poslanie Osuského v Europe v júni 916?" Slovak v Amerike, 1967 December 20. (Folder 68: 4)
  - "Bolshevik Dictatorship," 1968? (Folder 68: 5)
  - Article on the 50th anniversary of Czechoslovakia's independence, České listy, 1968 September. (Folder 68: 6)
  - Speech on the founding of Czechoslovakia, Světový kongress Slováků, 1971? (Folder 68: 7)
  - "How Czechoslovakia Was Born," 1971 June 17. (Folder 68: 8)
- Career File, 1918-1973. (Box 69-87)
  Articles, brochures, chronological records, contracts, correspondence, interviews, itinerary, lists, memoranda, messages, newsletters, notes, outlines, programs, reports, schedules, statements, study, survey, clippings, and miscellany relating to professional activities of Štefan Osuský, arranged chronologically by name of government agency or organization. See also Correspondence
  - Czechoslovakia. Vyslanectví (Great Britain) [Czechoslovak Envoy Extraordinary and Minister Plenipotentiary, 1918 September - 1921 January] (Folder 69: 1)
  - Paris Peace Conference [Secretary General, later Delegate, of the Czechoslovak Delegation, 1919 January - 1920]
    - General
      - Article 250 (Folder 69: 2)
      - Article 267 (Folder 69: 3)
      - Article 296 (Folder 69: 4)
      - Declaration of the Slovaks (Folder 69: 5)
      - Letter to Alexandre Millerand (Folder 69: 6)
      - Memoranda
        - Clémenceau, Georges, to the President of the Austrian Delegation (Folder 69: 7)
        - Renner, Karl, to the President of the Conference (Folder 69: 8)
      - Speech by H. H. Asquith, "Discours prononcé à Paisley le 6 février" (Folder 69: 9)
      - Writings (authors unknown)
        - "Un Bolchévique à la Conférence de la Paix" (Folder 69: 10)
        - "The Struggle for Supremacy in Eastern Europe" (Folder 69: 11)
        - "L'accomplissement de l'histoire" (Folder 69: 12)
    - Agrarian reform - Czechoslovakia (Folder 69: 13)
    - Commission on Reparation of Damage (Folder 69: 14)
    - Czechoslovak Delegation (Folder 69: 15-16)
    - Hungarian Delegation. (Folder 69: 17-18)
      Includes "Instruction confidentielle du ministère magyare aux journaux et à ses agents"
    - Hungary (Folder 69: 19-20)
    - Italy (Folder 69: 21)
    - Poland (Folder 69: 22)
    - Reparations Commission (Folder 69: 23)
    - Reparations (Folder 69: 24-25)
    - Romanian Delegation (Folder 69: 26)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 69: 27)
  - League of Nations [Czechoslovak delegate, 1919-1937; Czechoslovak representative to the Reparations Commission, 1919 November - 1932; Chairman of the Supervisory Commission, 1923-1937] (Box 70)
    - General
      - Album of drawings by Oscar Lazar, depicting members of the 7th Assembly, 1926 (Folder 70: 1)
      - Clippings (Folder 70: 2-3)
      - Communication of Beneš (Folder 70: 4)
      - Financial statement, 1938 March 31 (Folder 70: 5)
      - Letter from the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Republic of Czechoslovakia, appointing Osuský to be a delegate to the 4th Assembly, 1923 August 27 (Folder 70: 6)
      - Program (Folder 70: 7-9)
      - Publications - Journal des Nations (Folder 70: 10)
      - Report on the work of the League, 1941-1942 (Folder 70: 11)
    - Financial Committee. Letter to the President of the Financial Committee (Box-folder 71: 1)
    - Hungary (Folder 71: 2-3)
    - International Institute of Intellectual Cooperation (Folder 71: 4)
    - Reparations (Folder 71: 5)
    - Special Committee on Contributions (Folder 71: 6)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 71: 7)
  - Czechoslovakia. Vyslanectví (France) [Minister Plenipotentiary, 1921 January - 1940 June]
    - General
      - Correspondence
        - 1935-1939. (Folder 71: 8)
          Includes letters from Jan Masaryk to Samuel Hoare, 1938 March 23; and a letter from Jan Krofta to Lord Halifax, 1938 September 28, and answer from Lord Halifax
        - 1940 January-June (Folder 71: 9)
      - Instructions of Osuský to Czech consulates in France, 1939 April 11 (Folder 71: 10)
      - List of employees before World War II (Folder 71: 11)
      - Minutes of meetings, Paris, 1939 (Box 72)
        - November 6 (Folder 72: 1)
        - November 9 (Folder 72: 2)
        - December 3 (Folder 72: 3)
      - Social agenda (Folder 72: 4)
    - Finances (Folder 72: 5-10)
    - Formation of the Czechoslovak Army in France (Box 73)
      - General. (Folder 73: 1)
        Includes a report by the Army attaché in Paris, Kalina, on his activities after March 15, 1939
      - Agreement ("Accord relatif à la reconstitution en France de l'armée tchéchoslovaque," 1939 October 2) (Folder 73: 2)
      - Clippings. (Folder 73: 3-4)
        Includes issues of Československý Boj and Úřední Věstník Československý
      - Notes and communiques sent by Osuský to the French government (Folder 73: 5)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 73: 6)
  - Czechoslovak National Committee (Československý Národní Výbor), formed in Paris, on October 17, 1939, officially recognized by the French government on November 16, 1939 [Head of Správa Záhraničních Věcí Československých, 1939 November - 1940 June]
    - General
      - Conscription order, 1939 November 17 (Folder 73: 7)
      - Correspondence 1939 November - 1940 June (Folder 73: 8)
      - List of employees (Folder 73: 9)
      - Notes by Osuský. (Box-folder 74: 1)
        Includes notes on General Prchala
      - Proclamation (Folder 74: 2)
      - Publications - Úřední Věstník Československý. (Folder 74: 3)
        Includes Volume I, Number 1, with the original text of the agreement on the reconstitution of the Czechoslovak Army in France
      - Statutes (Folder 74: 4)
      - Summary of events, compiled by Osuský, leading to the fall of France, 1940 June 9 to June 25. (Folder 74: 5)
        Includes clippings and handwritten notes
      - Transcript of RFC broadcast (Folder 74: 6)
    - Evacuation, 1940 June. (Folder 74: 7-8)
      Includes some correspondence, notes by Osuský, and his "K poradní zprávě o organisačním a právním stavu vojenské správy." Also includes Vladimir Lezak-Borin, "La crise de l'armée tchéco-slovaque en France"
    - Formation (Folder 74: 9)
    - Recognition by France. (Folder 74: 10)
      Includes a letter from Edouard Daladier, 1939 November 14
    - Správa pro Službu Informační (Folder 74: 11)
    - Správa Socialní a Zdravotní (Folder 74: 12)
    - Správa Vojenská (Folder 74: 13)
    - Správa Záhraničních Věcí Československých (Folder 74: 14)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 74: 15)
  - Czechoslovak Government-in-Exile (provisional government formed on July 22, 1940, as a continuation of the Czechoslovak National Committee in London) [Minister of State, 1940 July - 1942 March] (Box 75)
    - General.
      Correspondence, including of Ministerstvo financí (Ministry of Finance), Ministerstvo národní obrany (Ministry of National Defense), Ministerstvo vnitra (Ministry of the Interior), Ministerstvo zahraničních věcí (Ministry of Foreign Affairs), Louis Doun (Military Advisers to the censorship), and Státní rada
      - 1940 July - December (Folder 75: 1)
      - 1941 (Folder 75: 2-3)
      - 1942 March (Folder 75: 4)
    - Finances (Folder 75: 5)
    - Formation (Folder 75: 6)
    - Political trial against Osuský (Box 76)
      - Correspondence, including with Edvard Beneš, František Černý, Maurice Dejean, Václav Kalina, Karel Lisický, Jan Šrámek, Karel Vanek (Folder 76: 1-3)
      - Notes by Osuský (Folder 76: 4-7)
      - Response of Osuský, "Réponse de M. Štefan Osuský à Vl. Klecanda, le Ministre Juraj Slavik, le Général Sergej Ingr, Dr. Edvard Outrata, les Secrétaires d'Etat Dr. Hubert Ripka et J. Becko," 1942 February 25. (Folder 76: 8)
        Holograph and typescript (in English, French, and Slovak)
    - Státní rada (National Council) (Box 77)
      - Minutes of meetings, relating to the political trial against Osuský
        - 1940 (Folder 77: 1)
        - 1941 (Folder 77: 2)
        - 1942 (Folder 77: 3-9)
        - 1944 (Folder 77: 10)
      - Notes by Osuský (Folder 77: 11-12)
      - Program (Folder 78: 1)
      - Publications - Zprávy Státní rady (Folder 78: 2)
      - Statutes (Folder 78: 3)
  - The 'Never Again' Association [Vice-president, 1943?]. (Folder 78: 4)
    Includes correspondence and minutes of meetings
  - Council of Free Czechoslovakia (U.S.) [Co-founder and chairman, later president of the Central Committee, 1949-?]
    - Circulars (Folder 78: 5)
    - Correspondence
      - General. (Folder 78: 6-8)
        Includes the letter of resignation of Ferdinand Peroutka
      - Assembly of Captive European Nations (Folder 78: 9)
      - United States. Senate (Folder 78: 10)
    - Declarations (Box-folder 79: 1)
    - List of members (Folder 79: 2)
    - Memoranda (Folder 79: 3)
    - Minutes (Folder 79: 4)
    - Notes by Osuský (Folder 79: 5)
    - Program (Folder 79: 6)
    - Publications
      - Hlas Československa (Folder 79: 7)
      - Modrá revue (Folder 79: 8)
    - Speeches (Folder 79: 9)
    - Statutes (Folder 79: 10)
    - Subject file
      - Forced Labor (Folder 79: 11)
      - Founding of the Council. (Folder 79: 12-13)
        Includes correspondence with the United States Department of State, memoranda, and the text of the Declaration of the Council
    - Miscellaneous materials and clippings (Folder 79: 14-15)
  - National Committee for a Free Europe [Advisor, 1950-1962] (Box 80)
    - Correspondence (Folder 80: 1-2)
    - Publications
      - East Europe (formerly News from Behind the Iron Curtain) (Folder 80: 3)
      - Free Europe Press (Folder 80: 4)
      - News from Czechoslovakia (Folder 80: 5)
      - Operation Veto (Folder 80: 6)
      - Report on Czechoslovakia (published by the Research and Information Center, N.Y.) (Folder 80: 7)
    - Radio broadcast transcripts
      - Radio Free Europe. (Folder 80: 8-10)
        Includes special report entitled "European 'Supranational' Organizations," Radio Free Europe Story, transcripts of special commentaries by Osuský, and some correspondence
      - Voice of America (Folder 80: 11)
    - Speeches. (Folder 81: 1)
      Includes an address by John Foster Dulles entitled "The Pursuit of Liberty"
    - Subject file
      - The "Black Book" (Folder 81: 2-3)
      - Mid-European Law Project (Folder 81: 4-6)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 81: 7)
  - International Commission of Jurists [Member, 1952-1973; in 1971, elected Honorary Member of the Commission] (Box 82)
    - Basic facts (Folder 82: 1)
    - Conference and congress proceedings (Folder 82: 2-9)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 83: 1-2)
    - Memoranda (Folder 83: 3)
    - Minutes of meetings (Folder 83: 4)
    - Press releases (Folder 83: 5)
    - Publications. (Folder 83: 6)
      Includes bulletins of the Commission
    - Reports of the Secretary General (Folder 83: 7)
    - Speech by Osuský entitled "Appraisal of Results," The International Congress of Jurists, Athens, Greece, 1955 September 20. (Folder 83: 8)
    - Statements and resolutions (Box-folder 84: 1)
    - Statutes (Folder 84: 2)
    - Working paper on civil and political rights (Folder 84: 3)
  - Council of Free Jurists from Countries Behind the Iron Curtain [Founder, 1952 November?]
    - Memorandum on the establishment of an "International Law Organization" (Folder 84: 4)
    - Report by Osuský entitled "Organization of a Council of Free Jurists from Countries Behind the Iron Curtain" (Folder 84: 5)
  - International Association of Democratic Lawyers [Member]. (Folder 84: 6-8)
    Includes proceedings of the 6th Congress, Brussels, 1956 May 22-25, a paper by Osuský entitled "Co-existence pacifique," and his notes
  - Assembly of Captive European Nations (ACEN) [Founding member, 1954?] (Box 85)
    - Charter and rules of procedure (Folder 85: 1)
    - Correspondence (Folder 85: 2)
    - Declarations (Folder 85: 3)
    - Memoranda (Folder 85: 4)
    - Minutes of meetings (Folder 85: 5)
    - Notes by Osuský (Folder 85: 6)
    - Publications - ACEN News (Folder 85: 7)
    - Reports, including by Osuský, entitled "Legal Defence of the Socialist Economic Order of the Czechoslovak Socialist Republic" and "Report on Soviet Impact on International Law," presented at a conference organized by the Duke University School of Law, 1964 February 28-29, and a "Draft of a Letter to the Rockefeller Panel," 1960 January 8 (Folder 85: 8-11)
    - Resolutions (Folder 86: 1)
    - Speeches by Osuský
      - Speech, opening plenary meeting, first session, Carnegie Endowment International Center, New York, 1954 September 20. (Folder 86: 2)
      - Speech, plenary meeting, first session, Carnegie Endowment International Center, New York, 1954 October 22. (Folder 86: 3)
      - Speech, 36th anniversary of Czechoslovakia's independence, Carnegie Endowment International Center, New York, 1954 October 28. (Folder 86: 4)
      - Closing speech, 1954 December 21. (Folder 86: 5)
      - "The Poznan Trial," 1956 September 27. (Folder 86: 6)
      - Speech, plenary meeting, 1956 November 13. (Folder 86: 7)
      - Speech, plenary meeting, 1957 October 3. (Folder 86: 8)
      - Speech on the Soviet slogan of 'peaceful co-existence,' 55th meeting, plenary assembly, Carnegie Hall, 1957 December 11. (Folder 86: 9)
        Typescript. Includes correspondence
      - Speech, plenary meeting, 1959 December 10. (Folder 86: 10)
      - Special commentary on the meeting of the Assembly of Captive European Nations, Radio Free Europe, 1961? (Folder 86: 11)
    - Statements (Folder 86: 12)
    - Miscellaneous materials and clippings (Folder 86: 13)
  - Council of Europe [Chairman, European Political Community]
    - Memorandum by Osuský entitled "European Integration," prepared for Drew Pearson, Washington, D.C., 1955 April 4. (Folder 86: 14)
    - Minutes of meetings (Folder 86: 15)
    - Notes by Osuský (Folder 86: 16)
    - Papers by Osuský (Folder 86: 17)
    - Publications (Folder 86: 18-19)
    - Reports (Box 87)
      - General. (Folder 87: 1)
        Includes the bi-monthly report on current activities of the Council of Europe, 1953 November-December
      - Osuský
        - "Collaboration of Exiles From Behind the Iron Curtain with the Council of Europe," n.d. (Folder 87: 2)
        - "Integration of Europe," n.d. (Folder 87: 3)
        - "On the Prevailing Climate in Western Europe," Washington, D.C., 1956 June 16. (Folder 87: 4)
      - Thorbecke, William J., "European Federation" (Folder 87: 5)
    - Statute. (Folder 87: 6)
      Includes a paper by Nikolai Balabanoff entitled "Resume of the History and Development of the Council of Europe" and a report by Raoul Bossy entitled "Panel for European Political Community and Cooperation with the Council of Europe"
    - Subject file
      - Consultative Assembly sessions (Folder 87: 7)
      - European Political Community
        - Memorandum by Osuský entitled "The Drafting of the Constitution of the European Political Community" and "Co-Operation of the European Political Community with States not Its Members and with International Institutions" (Folder 87: 8)
        - Minutes of meetings (Folder 87: 9)
        - Papers (Folder 87: 10)
  - Court of World Public Opinion, International Communism on Trial, 1968 February 19-21 [Judge] (Folder 87: 11-14)
- Pavla Osuská File, 1938-1978. (Box 88)
  Correspondence and minutes of meetings relating to professional activities of Pavla Osuská, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Correspondence
    - General (Folder 88: 1)
    - Benešová, Hana, 1940 (Folder 88: 2)
    - Černý, Zdeněk, 1948-1957 (Folder 88: 3)
    - La Croix-Rouge Française, 1949 (Folder 88: 4)
    - Czechoslovak Relief, 1940 (Folder 88: 5)
    - Czechoslovakia. Government-in-Exile. Ministerstvo sociální péče (Ministry of Social Affairs), 1940 (Folder 88: 6)
    - Daladier, Edouard, 1968 (Folder 88: 7)
    - Fiala, Karel, 1940 (Folder 88: 8)
    - Hromádka, 1944 (Folder 88: 9)
    - Kahlerová, Charlotte, 1940 (Folder 88: 10)
    - Kopecký, 1974 (Folder 88: 11)
    - Masaryk Institute, n.d. (Folder 88: 12)
    - Milec, Leos, 1966-1978 (Folder 88: 13)
    - The National Conference on Freedom and Peace Through Liberation, 1953-1954 (Folder 88: 14)
    - Sdružení Československých Politických Uprchlíků v Německu (Alliance of the Czechoslovak Political Refugees in Germany), 1952-1956 (Folder 88: 15)
    - Société Générale, 1938 (Folder 88: 16)
  - Soumar, Bohuslav, 1968 (Folder 88: 17)
  - Sturm, Rudolf, 1968 (Folder 88: 18)
  - Svaz Československých Politických Věznů (Union of Czechoslovak Political Prisoners), 1953 (Folder 88: 19)
  - Světový Kongres Slováků, 1973-1974 (Folder 88: 20)
  - Tabouis, Geneviève, 1967-1973 (Folder 88: 21)
  - Trnka, Jaroslav, 1941-1978 (Folder 88: 22)
  - Vnuk, 1977 (Folder 88: 23)
  - Subject file
    - American Fund for Czechoslovak Refugees, Inc. (Folder 88: 24)
    - Cooperative for American Remittances to Everywhere, Inc. (CARE) (Folder 88: 25)
    - Czechoslovak National Council of Women in Exile
      - Correspondence
        - General (Folder 88: 26)
        - Refugee camps
          - Austria (Folder 88: 27)
          - Germany (Folder 88: 28-31)
          - Italy (Folder 88: 32)
      - Minutes of meetings (Folder 88: 33)
    - The National Council of Women of the United States (Folder 88: 34)
- Subject File, 1910-1992. (Box 89-102)
  Articles, brochures, clippings, comments, maps, organizational records, programs, proposals, reports, speeches, writings, printed matter, and miscellany relating to various persons, organizations and countries, arranged alphabetically by subject. See also Career File
  Articles, brochures, comments, maps, organizational records, press releases, programs, proposals, reports, clippings and other printed matter.
  - Académie Diplomatique Internationale, Paris (Folder 89: 1)
  - Action Committee for the United States of Europe (Folder 89: 2)
  - Agence Havas (Folder 89: 3)
  - Allied and Associated Powers (1914-1920) (Folder 89: 4)
  - The Allied Circle (Folder 89: 5)
  - Allied Powers War Service Act (1942) (Folder 89: 6)
  - American Fund for Czechoslovak Refugees (Folder 89: 7)
  - American Management Association (Folder 89: 8)
  - American Newsletter, 1943 October 5 (Folder 89: 9)
  - Anglo-American Press Banquet (Folder 89: 10)
  - Association of Allied Professors and Lecturers in Great Britain (Folder 89: 11)
  - Association of American Correspondents in London (Folder 89: 12)
  - Atlantic Charter (1941) (Folder 89: 13)
  - Atlantic Community (Folder 89: 14)
  - Auschwitz (Poland: Concentration camp). Reports by former inmates (Folder 89: 15)
  - Beneš, Edvard., See also Speeches and Writings/1941 March 8, and Career File
    - Correspondence (Folder 89: 16-17)
    - Decrees (Folder 89: 18)
    - Excerpts from Historický Časopis (Folder 89: 19)
    - Speeches and lectures (Box 90)
      - General. (Folder 90: 1)
        Bound copy of newspaper clippings
      - "Christmas Message" (Folder 90: 2)
      - "Czechoslovakia Lives: Her Place in a Free Europe" (Folder 90: 3)
      - "My Fears and My Hopes" (Folder 90: 4)
      - "Návrh na zřízení Národní rady" (Folder 90: 5)
      - "Pravda o Haagu" (Folder 90: 6)
      - "Přerod a budoucnost poválečné demokracie" (Folder 90: 7)
      - "The Present War and the Future Peace" (Folder 90: 8)
    - Writings about Beneš
      - "Beneš' Policy during the Second World War," Josef Kalvoda, a series of articles, published in Národní Politika, 1975 (in English, Czech, and French) (Folder 90: 9-11)
      - "Les illusions de M. Beneš," Gabriel Puaux (Folder 90: 12)
      - "Short extract from the Memorial on the Recognition of Dr. Beneš as President of Czechoslovakia and of his Government" (Folder 90: 13)
      - "Visite à Mme Beneš" (in French) (Folder 90: 14)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 90: 15)
  - Birkenau (Germany: Concentration camp). Reports by former inmates (Box-folder 91: 1)
  - Briand, Aristide (Folder 91: 2)
  - Bureau de Presse Tchécoslovaque, Paris (Folder 91: 3)
  - Catroux, General - Mission to North Africa, 1943 (Folder 91: 4)
  - Cechoslovak (Folder 91: 5)
  - Central European Commonwealth. Extract from Milan Hodža, "Federation in Central Europe" (Folder 91: 6)
  - Centre d'Etudes de l'Europe Centrale et Danubienne (Folder 91: 7)
  - Cercle Franco-Tchécoslovaque (Folder 91: 8)
  - Československá Obec Sokolská (Czechoslovak Sokols) (Folder 91: 9)
  - Československé Sdružení pro Evropské Hnutí (Czechoslovak Union for European Movement) (Folder 91: 10)
  - Československý Červený Kříž (Czechoslovak Red Cross)
    - Financial records (Folder 91: 11)
    - Stamps (Folder 91: 12)
    - Statutes (Folder 91: 13)
  - Chalons-Tahure (France: Camp). Itinerary of the visit of T. G. Masaryk (Folder 91: 14)
  - Chassinat-Gigot (Folder 91: 15)
  - China (Folder 91: 16)
  - Cleveland Agreement of October 22, 1915 (Folder 91: 17)
  - Colonie Tchecoslovaque, Paris (Folder 91: 18)
  - Comité d'Aide Sociale aux Réfugiés Tchécoslovaques (Folder 91: 19)
  - Communist countries - Religion. (Folder 91: 20)
    Issues of Religion in Communist Dominated Areas
  - Confrérie des Chevaliers de la Chantepleure (Folder 91: 21)
  - Congress of Czechs and Slovaks (Folder 91: 22)
  - Conseil de l'Entente Balkanique (Folder 91: 23)
  - Czech-German specialized dictionary (Folder 91: 24)
  - Czech Labour Union (Folder 91: 25)
  - Czech Refugee Trust Fund (Folder 91: 26)
  - Czechoslovak National Council in Paris (Česko-slovenská národní rada v Paříži) (Folder 91: 27)
  - Czechoslovak National Council of America (Československá národní rada v Americe) (Folder 91: 28)
  - Czechoslovak Research Institute, London (Box-folder 92: 1-2)
  - Czechoslovak-Polish Confederation (Proposed). (Folder 92: 3-4)
    Includes statutes and regulations, and Beneš's speech "One Pillar of Future Peace in Central Europe: How Czechoslovakia and Poland Visualise Their Post-War Confederation," 1941 November 11
  - Czechoslovakia
    - General (Folder 92: 5-7)
    - Economic conditions - 1918-1945 (Folder 92: 8-11)
    - Foreign relations
      - General. (Folder 93: 1)
        Includes "Poznámky k naší činnosti v zahraničí" by Josef Malik
      - France - Monument at Darney (Folder 93: 2-3)
      - Germany., See Germany - Foreign relations
      - Great Britain. Financial agreement (Folder 93: 4-5)